[Music]
if you use financial reporting and
Telemetry and have an interest in
auditing let me show you what we are
cooking on for the 2025 release wave
1 here on the Finance on the finance
reporting I have uh some different
reports and let me just create a new one
let's say uh
cooking cooking demo report for
financial reporting we all do that let's
pick a row definition a column
definition I love this BBD r c r EB it's
amazing there you go and we are done so
I have not now created a new report and
um let me just to do a change to my
report maybe I want to change my road
definition actually I want to create a
new row definition let's call it cook
and this is a cooking row
definition
okay and here's my cooking and I would I
might also want to do a column
definition just for fun so let me just
add a new column let's say a cooking uh
cooking show so let's call it a cooking
show
column and you kind of get the idea I
have created a report I created two row
column row definition and maybe I want
to change the report to uh something
else let me just uh do that edit report
definition change this to cooking demo
to there we go
and it has been saved all
good so these are all changes to
financial
reporting why like what's going on with
Telemetry well let because I did turn on
Telemetry for this environment let's
switch to application insights and run a
little
query all right so here in application
insights I wrote a little custo query we
take traces from the last day I'm
filtering on my own user telemeter ID
this GID is safe you can't hack me with
this this is just a GID from my test
environment so
relax uh take the latest events first
and then we project timestamp message
event ID and some custom dimensions and
we take the first 100 let's let's run
this and see what's cooking here oh look
we have if I just scroll back a little
bit in time
here we
[Music]
go so you see we have an event financial
report created where we lock the report
definition code I also did a
modification then I have Telemetry for
the creation of report row definitions
with this event and if I scroll here to
the to the right you can see that we
have the road def definition code loged
there and also similar life cycle events
for creating column definitions with the
column defition definition code and so
on and if I had done a little bit more
in in the demo like modifying a ro
column definition you would have seen
that deleting a row column or report
definition you would have seen that and
even running a financial report you
would also see the usage Telemetry now
here in version 2025
release wave one pretty cool eh